YAN BONNEL

JAVA AND ANDROID DEVELOPPER

ybonnel@gmail.com https://github.com/ybonnel

Twiter: @ybonnel

Profile

Developper with 7 years experience on Java ecosystem and more recently (about 2 years) on native Android development.

Skills

Java I work with java for 7 years, like very much all ecosystem,

go to JUG, Devoxx,

...

Android

I develop on Android for 2 years on personnal projects

HTML5

I'm interrested on new HTML technologies (like JQuery, Angular.js, JQuery Mobile, Twitter bootstrap).

Continous delivery

I like work to automate everything to have a real continous delivery

Technical

Java	Hibernate	HTML5	Jenkins
JEE	Play framework	CSS	Sonar
Spring	Android	Javascript/JQuery	Maven

Experience

Sopra Group Software Architect

02/2008 - now

Transversal technical leader on 4 Java applications, team of 30 people (05/2012 to now)

Applications in charge of network activation for a french mobile operator.

New application management contract with reversibily.

Work in team with Indian people.

Functions

- Continous delivery: define build and installation process with Jenkins for all applications.
- Technical expert : support for all developper.
- Help to resolve issues on multiple environments.
- Realisation of a Web portal for developpers (Play framework).

Technologies:

- Java
- Ant
- Jboss
- Oracle
- Unix
- Jenkins
- Play Framework
- o SVN

Technical leader on two Java applications, team of 100 to 200 people (02/2008 - 04-2012)

Redisign project of the core system for a french mobile operator. This project cover from Order to Billing with offers catalogue.

Functions

• Bench of Cameleon Software (used for Offers Catalogue) - 5 month

- Use of Load Runner
- Development of a Webservice layer to abstract Cameleon (Jboss WS)
- Writing functionnal specifications for Offers Catalogue 6 month
- o Technical Leader on Offers Catalogue, 5 to 10 developpers 1 years
 - Webservices (JbossWS)
 - Hibernate
 - Continous Integration (Maven, Hudson, Sonar)
- o Technical Leader on Taking Order System, 10 to 30 developpers more than 2 years
 - Webservices (CXF)
 - Spring core, JPA, Hibernate
 - Continous Integration (Maven, Jenkins, Sonar)
 - Installation and integration of Gerrit (software to help in code revue).
 - Realisation of a Web Portal for developpers (Play Framework)

Technologies:

- Java
- Spring core
- Jboss
- · Hibernate, JPA
- Webservices (JbossWS and CXF)
- o Oracle
- Unix
- Maven
- Jenkins
- o Play Framework
- o SVN
- Git (used for Web Portal)

Sopra Group

Junior Software Architect

11/2007 - 01/2008

Create an UI to manage documents (team of 5 people).

Application in charge of the documents management for all exploitation documents

Functions:

- In part of study before the realisation
- Creation of the base for the rest of developments.

Technologies:

- Java/JEE
- Struts
- Hibernate
- SVN

Sopra Group

07/2006 - 10/2007

Developper

Part in all steps of an Application Management Contact (team of 4 to 10 people)

 $Applications \ used \ for \ a \ mobile \ operator \ to \ know \ the \ list \ of \ network \ antennas \ will \ be \ used \ by \ users.$

Functions

- $\circ~$ C++ developments under Unix for an activation system.
- $\circ~$ JEE developments for an administration interface.
- Java developments under Windows for a forecasting system radio coverage.
- · Participation in specifications and testing for this applications.

Technologies:

- o C++
- o Unix/Shell

- Java/JEE
- Struts
- o PVCS Version Manager
- VBScripts

Sopra Group

02/2006 - 06/2006

Developper

Final-year internship

Part in development of an activation system for a french mobile operator.

- C++ developments under Unix (HP UX)
- Unix Scripting (KSH)

Off-work projects

Transports Rennes and Transports Bordeaux github.com/ybonnel/TransportsRennes

08/2010 - now

Android applications for public transport of Rennes and Bordeaux. Use of Open-Data for this two cities.

Some statistics:

- o Transports Rennes downloads: more than 19 000
- $\circ~$ Transports Rennes comments : more than 500 ratings with 4.642/5 as average
- Transports Bordeaux downloads: more than 18 000
- Transports Bordeaux comments: more thant 250 ratings with 4.627/5 as average
- Code base: more thant 30 000 LOC (Project is on ohloh)

CsvEngine

05/2011 - now

github.com/ybonnel/CsvEngine

Small java framework based on annotations used to parse and write CSV files.

Transports Rouen

07/2012 - now

github.com/ybonnel/TransportsRouen http://transports-rouen.appspot.com

Small mobile web app for public bikes in Rouen Used to test JQuery Mobile technology

BreizhCamp github.com/breizhjug

2011 - now

Part in all developments for web application for BreizhCamp. BreizhCamp is two days conferences organized by the JUG of Rennes.

Education

University of La Rochelle (France)

2000 - 2006

Master in computer science (speciality: pattern recognition and image processing).